Irene Alegre

Profile

Senior Product Designer with 5+ years of design experience and 7+ years of startup experience. I have experience working on a whole range of **B2B products**, from **dashboards** to manage your stock, customer conversations and sales, to analytics platforms, bespoke internal tools, content management and project management systems and AR visualisation apps that clients can embed into their e-commerce websites.

Relevant work experience

Senior Product Designer

Jul 2019 – Present

at Poplar Studio

As the sole designer at Poplar Studio, I have worked on a large number of products over the years, from Project Management platforms to Content Management Systems for 3D files and AR visualisation units.

UX/UI Designer at Wayhome

Nov 2018 - May 2019

Developed numerous marketing programs (logos, brochures, newsletters, infographics, presentations, and advertisements) and guaranteed that they exceeded the expectations of our clients.

Product Designer at carwow

Mar 2018 - Oct 2018

I joined the Dealership Platform Team at carwow, who worked on building out and improving the B2B platform dealerships used to handle customer inquiries and relationships, review sales and manage their stock.

Marketing Campaign Manager & Designer

Jun 2015 – Jul 2017

I began at Onfido as a content creator when the team consisted of only three people, but slowly evolved into more of a Digital Marketing role where I looked after online campaigns, landing page creation and metrics.

Contacts

O London, UK

irenealegre.com

07512227985

Hard skills

O Figma & FigJam

O Prototyping

O Wireframing

O User flows

User personas

O UX Research

User interviews

User testing

Agile methodologies

Soft skills

• Communicating design decisions

• Working in cross-functional teams

Leading design department

Owning design process

Irene Alegre

Previous work experience

I haven't always been a designer, and so I've worn many hats over the years. Below are some of the roles I've had that have influenced me the most, both on a personal and professional level.

Editorial work

I have also worked in the publishing industry in a variety of roles; I have written interior and product design books (commissioned), been an editorial assistant for a small independent publisher and done marketing work for an academic publisher.

English teacher

I've both tutored one on one and taught small groups of children ages (4-16) and young adults. I learned how to handle frustration on both ends (mine and theirs), and a few of my students taught me a thing or two about life.

Bank teller at BBVA Bank

I did this job on and off on a temporary basis, and it taught me how to work under pressure, to be resourceful when technology inevitable fails you and to handle customers dealing with sensitive issues such as their financial difficulties.

Education

UX Design Immersive (2017)

General Assembly London, UK

Master in Publishing (2012)

IDEC – Pompeu Fabra Barcelona, Spain

Degree in English (2005-2011)

University of Barcelona Barcelona, Spain